Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/lindseylacross (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Hospitality

Customer Service

Restaurants

Languages

Spanish

Certifications

Hearst INCLUDE Certified Change Agent

Hearst Leadership Development Program

Honors-Awards

UVM Political Science Departmental Honors Program

Deans List

Cum Laude

Lindsey Lawrence

Digital Sales Manager, Hearst Television South Burlington, Vermont, United States

Summary

Over my near decade in advertising sales for Hearst Television, I have held positions in several capacities and was most recently promoted to Digital Sales Manager at NBC5. My current role focuses on managing budget achievement across a range of platforms and coaching a team of Account Executives to success in selling a versatile portfolio of digital ad solutions, with local, regional and national placements.

Experience

NBC5

10 years 7 months

Digital Sales Manager

September 2021 - Present (2 years 3 months)

South Burlington, Vermont, United States

After a proven tract record in digital revenue and a recognized sense of interest, I was promoted to Digital Sales Manager in 2021. In this role, my focus shifted from TV to Digital but I maintained similar responsibilities as my LSM role. I am my sales team's digital expert and conduit between Hearst's corporate digital leadership and our Account Executives (AE). Digital opportunities have expanded exponentially in the last few years, and with that our clients range from local to national. I represent local site/app, OTT streaming video, native content, and programmatic video and display. I collaborate with AEs on client strategy and digital product positioning, often attending client meetings to educate and consult our clients on best digital practices and approach. My passion and expertise has translated to record revenue in several product lines, as has contributed to a refined, educated, and digital savvy sales team.

Local Sales Manager

January 2016 - September 2021 (5 years 9 months)

South Burlington, Vermont, United States

Responsible for managing a team of 9 Account Executives (AE) who were selling our broadcast affiliates, NBC and The Valley CW. In the first few years, I was dedicated primarily to the cultivation and growth of our brand-new CW Network affiliate and dedicated sellers, evolving over to NBC after we combined our two sales teams. My work involved weekly coaching and 1 on 1s with AEs to ensure individual budget success, TV budgeting and forecasting, contributing to weekly sales meetings and product lessons, and supporting AEs on client strategy and pitching. I was also a direct-report for up to 50% of sellers which brought HR requirements and general leadership responsibilities.

Account Executive

December 2013 - December 2015 (2 years 1 month)

Burlington, Vermont Area

In this client-facing role I was responsible for generating new business revenue across all platforms, while managing and cultivating an active account list. My business development came in the form of cold-calling local and regional businesses, creating and delivering sales presentations, and closing business to ensure all revenue goals were achieved. I was a successful self-starter and motivated by helping my client's grow through broadcast television and digital advertising. Product and market knowledge was critical, and just as crucial were my time management skills. I closed record digital revenue and earned the Hearst Eagle Award for Sales Excellence in my 2nd year of selling, 2015, before being promoted to management in January 2016.

Local Sales Assistant May 2013 - December 2013 (8 months)

Colchester, Vermont

Supported the NBC5 sales team with duties such as, but not limited too, campaign order entry, account maintenance, and reporting. Became an expert in our team's selling tools with the goal of growing into the Account Executive role in the future. I was promoted after 8 months.

University of Vermont
Student Legal Services Intern
September 2012 - May 2013 (9 months)

Burlington, Vermont Area

As an intern with Student Legal Services at the University of Vermont, it was my responsibility to attend weekly meetings and hold office hours. UVM students can come to our office hours when they are seeking legal advice. I met with clients and took down incident information, which I then presented to my presiding attorneys in order to seek a resolution or advice. I advised

my clients based on how the attorneys advised me. I maintained client relationships by updating case statuses, seeking information, guiding clients, and often attending University hearings in off-campus court proceedings.

State of Vermont Legislative Intern January 2012 - May 2012 (5 months) Montpelier, Vermont

In this position I supported a party leader and was responsible for attending committee meetings, conducting research, contacting constituents, and often drafting memos or letters. I also worked on strategies for caucus management and organization with my supervisor. I also created spread sheets while collecting research and surveys for party members as organizational and informational tools.

Vermont Attorney General's Office, Consumer Assistance Program Consumer Advisor January 2012 - May 2012 (5 months)

As a Consumer Advisor I helped Vermonter's solve disputes with businesses, protect themselves from fraud, and seek available resources. The Consumer Assistance Program operates under the Vermont Attorney General's Office, and operates a consumer hotline, mediates consumer disputes with businesses, and tracks fraud or scam complaints. My job involved responding to Vermont consumers who contacted the office either by phone or by submitting a complaint, analyzing submitted complaints for fraudulent or outstanding activities, and working to help effectively solve those disputes.

Education

University of Vermont
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Political Science · (2009 - 2013)

Colchester High School
High School Diploma, High School (2005 - 2009)